Ankit Chopade

https://aboutout.github.io/

PROFILE

Shri Guru Gobind Singhji Institute of Engineering and Technology graduate with Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering. Held internship focusing on Data Science and Machine Learning. Served on several college and fraternal committees.

EDUCATION

Shri Guru Gobind Singhji Institute of Engineering and Technology

Nanded,IND

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering; CGPA: 8.17

Aug. 2015 -- May. 2019

E-mail: chopadeankit1997@gmail.com

Mobile: (+91) 8149828009

PUBLICATIONS

Seven Class Classification of Skin Lesions by using Incremental Convolutional Neural Network in Python

Elsevier

Classification of Skin Lesions by using Extended Incremental Convolutional Neural Network

Built additional Data Science capabilities via online courses, off-campus courses and volunteering efforts.

IEEE

SKILLS & RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Languages: Python(dash, plotly, matplotlib, keras, sklearn), Java, SQL, PHP, C, JavaScript
- Techniques: Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Data Science, Computer Vision, Data Structure & Algorithms
- Tools/Packages: OpenCV, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Latex, RPA-Ui Path, Oracle, Tableau, Sybase, Putty, Autosys, ServiceNow
- Courses: Probability and Statistics in Data Science using Python, Python for Data Science, Python of Research, Cyber Security, Distributed Computing, Artificial Neural Network

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Intern Fusion Informatics limited

Mar. 2019 -- May. 2019

- > Work on ETL process, Business Intelligence Tools-Tableau and formulated Key Performance Indicators based on data
- > Developed dashboards for many domains like Social Media and developed modules for Business Intelligence ToolAI-Mind
- Assistant System Engineer-Trainee Tata Consultancy Services

June. 2019 -- Present

- > Working for the Morgan Stalnley as unix and database developer. I have developed and debug the stored procedures to resolve the issues faced. I am involved in Code level investigation of the Autosys jobs which are in UNIX Shell Scripting and SQL.
- > Prepared the report specifications and database designs to support reporting requirements.

PROJECTS

Chennai Water Management

Mar, 2019 -- Present

Technology: Python(matplotlib, pandas, numpy)

- > Visualize the water need / usage of the city, Identify whether the water sources availability will be able to meet the needs till the subsequent monsoon, How bad is the current water crisis compared to previous years.
- **Analyzing Space Launches with Python**

June. 2018 -- Dec. 2018

Technology: Python(seaborn, matplotlib, pandas, numpy)

- > In this project the launches done by various countries are analyze on various distinct parameters like launch dates, mission, type, agency, etc and four conclusions are drawn.
- > The launch agencies are also analyzed on parameters like count of launches, type, class, etc.

Paperless Submission

Medica

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Java, JSP

Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2017

- > This is a Web Application where Students can compile and run different types of programming languages (C, C++, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL) source code and can store their daily assignments provided during the practical sessions online.
- > Faculties can access the status of assignments of students by providing online grades automatically based on the Test Cases.

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Java, JSP

May. 2017 -- June 2017

- > I have developed the Web Application (Medica) where the patient can have the record of all its Medical Reports generated by any Medical authorities. The patient account is validated by its UID Number. The Medical authorities can access the patient account by using patient UID Number and UID of medical authorities.
- > Patient can access his account by using his/her UID Number and Password.

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES & OTHER COOL THINGS TO KNOW ABOUT ME

- Official Head Utsav 2018 Leads the event, manages the overall organization of more than 500 members and schedules.
- Student's Co-ordinator Pragyaa 2017 Planned and managed on ground activities and supervised more than 100 member crew.